Hi, I'm excited to share with
you this new course
on using LangChain to
chat with your data. This
is built in collaboration
with Harrison Chase, co-founder
and CEO of LangChain.
Large language models or
LLMs such as ChatGPT
can answer questions about
a lot of topics,
but an LLM in isolation knows
only what it was trained on,
which doesn't
include your personal data, such
as if you're in a company and have
proprietary documents not on
the internet, as well as data or articles
that were written after
the LLM was trained.
So wouldn't it be useful if you or
others such as your customers can
have a conversation with your own
documents and get
questions answered using
information from those
documents and using an LLM?
In this short course,
we will cover how to use
LangChain to chat with your data.
LangChain is an open-source
developer framework for
building LLM applications. LangChain
consists of several
modular components as
well as more end-to-end templates. The
modular components
in LangChain include
prompts, models, indexes, chains,
and agents. For
a more detailed look at these
components, you can see
our first course that I
taught with Andrew.
In this course, we will zoom in and
focus on one of the
more popular use cases of LangChain,
how to use LangChain
to chat with your data.
We will first cover how to
use LangChain document
loaders to load data from a
variety of exciting sources.
We will then touch on how
to split these
documents into semantically
meaningful chunks. This pre-processing
step may seem simple but
has a lot of nuance.
Next, we'll
give an overview of semantic search, a
basic method for
fetching relevant information
given a user question. This
is the easiest method
to get started with
but there are several
cases where it fails. We'll go
over these cases and then we'll go over
how to fix them. We'll then show how
to use those retrieved documents to
enable an LLM
to answer questions about a document
but show that you're still missing
one key piece in order
to fully recreate that chatbot experience.
Finally, we'll cover
that missing piece, memory,
and show how to build a
fully functioning chatbot through
which you can chat
with your data.
This will be an exciting short course.
We're grateful to Ankush Gola as well
as Lance Martin from the LangChain
team for working on all the
materials that you
hear Harrison present later, as
well as on the deeplearning.ai side,
Geoff Ladwig
and Diala Ezzeddine.
In case you're going through this course
and decide you'd like
a refresher on the basics of LangChain, I
encourage you to also
take that earlier short course on
LangChain for LLM
application development that
Harrison had mentioned
as well. But with
that, let us now go on to
the next video where
Harrison will show you
how to use LangChain's very convenient
collection of document
loaders.